t-systems.com 2010-05-26

# T-Systems: Privacy Policy

Thank you for visiting this website. T-Systems places great importance on data security and data protection. Protecting personal rights is integral to our corporate culture and built into our services and products. We respect the safety of your personal data. That is why T-Systems continuously works to improve data security measures to protect you and your privacy. 

This data protection statement explains what type of information we record when you visit our website, and how we use it. The statement does not apply to websites run by companies that are not part of T-Systems but who may provide a link to this or any other T-Systems web site. 

**Collection and use of personal data**

When you visit one of our websites, our web server temporarily records the following information for system security purposes: the domain name or IP address of the computer requesting access, the access date, the client’s file request (file name and URL), the HTTP response code and the website you are visiting from, and the number of bytes transferred over the connection. We may save some information in the form of cookies on your PC. A cookie is a piece of information that a website can send to your browser and save on your system. Cookies do not give us access to your system or your personal data. Please note that standard browser settings allow the use of cookies. If you do not want to allow the use of cookies, you can disable this option in your browser. We use cookies exclusively to tailor our website to your preferences. 

We do not collect personal data such as your name, address, phone number or e-mail address unless you provide this information voluntarily, for example as part of an information request, a competition, a job application or a request for information about an open position, etc. 

Personal data collected when visiting one of T-Systems’ websites is only used in accordance with the legal requirements of the state in which the T-Systems company is registered. 

**Use and transfer of this personal data**

We use your personal data only for the purpose of technical website administration and to meet your wishes and requirements, and solely for the specified purpose. 

Only with your express consent do we use the data for product-related surveys or marketing purposes, and even then only to the extent necessary for the specific instance. We only disclose data to official agencies if required by law. Our employees are required to maintain strict confidentiality. 

**Freedom of information**

Please send a request in writing to the relevant T-Systems company if you would like to know what personal data (e.g. name, address, etc.) we have stored about you. 

**Security**

To protect your personal data saved by us against unauthorized access and misuse, we have implemented extensive, state-of-the-art technical and organizational measures. 

**Contacts**

Please direct any questions, suggestions or specific requests to change, freeze or delete your personal data to T-Systems or, if known, directly to the company concerned. 

Data Protection Officer:  
Telekom Deutschland GmbH   
Konzerndatenschutz / Group Privacy   
Konzernbeauftragter für den Datenschutz / CPO   
Dr. Claus-Dieter Ulmer  
Friedrich-Ebert-Allee 140   
D-53113 Bonn
